Network Engineer

Network Engineer

Ocala, FL - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/71047439b2f5e833

A highly motivated, experienced (23+ years), and results oriented professional with notable success directing a broad range of enterprise networking services.

Willing to relocate to: Ocala, FL - Florida Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Network Engineer

Covenant Health Systems - Knoxville, TN - 2008 to Present

Network Engineer for a large, multi-campus regional healthcare system that includes multiple acute care hospitals, clinics, and primary care offices.

- Responsible for all aspects of a 10,000+ user metropolitan area network infrastructure.
- Responsible for designing, implementing and troubleshooting permanent and temporary network solutions.
- Troubleshooting and problem resolution of enterprise network difficulties and outages.
- Responsible for implementing/maintaining network connectivity to remote sites (ASE, MetroE, T1, T3, DSL, Cable).
- Maintain Cisco edge routers, HP core routers, and HP layer 3 edge switches.
- Build and maintain current Visio documentation for network infrastructure.
- Maintain Websense web proxy system and HP iMC network management platform.
- Maintain MRV DWDM equipment between Data Center and DR site.
- Maintain WhatsUpGold network monitoring system.
- Maintain nGenius Infinistream data collection and sniffer system.
- Maintain Cisco ASA VPN appliance with 100+ L2L VPN tunnels.

Network Engineer

Baptist Health Systems - East, Tennessee, US - 1996 to 2008

- Provided direct network support for a multi-campus healthcare system that included four hospitals, a regional cancer center, heart institute, senior health centers, pain institute, and doctors' office buildings.
- Responsible for all enterprise networking hardware including switches, routers, and firewalls.
- Installed and maintained Iprism Internet filtering appliance.
- Installed and administrated Cisco 3005 VPN concentrator.
- Performed daily network monitoring and troubleshooting with protocol analyzer/sniffer.
- Performed Domain Admin tasks including maintaining DNS and DHCP.

Field Service Engineer

IBM, TSS Division - Bradenton, FL - 1994 to 1996

- Performed daily computer/data-communications maintenance and repairs for 3000+ contracts within a large geographic area in Central Florida and East Tennessee.
- Installed, configured, and serviced all major brands of computers, printers, and related peripherals.
- Installed and configured both LAN and WAN hardware, including satellite communication equipment.

• Surpassed customer satisfaction goals throughout region.

Field Service Engineer

General Electric Computer Service - Bradenton, FL - 1992 to 1994

- Performed daily computer/data-communications maintenance and repairs within large geographic area throughout central Florida.
- Installed and serviced many types of computer hardware from desktops to high-end servers.
- Installed, configured, and maintained airline ticket systems.
- · Worked in a strong team oriented environment helping technicians in other areas as needed.

Base Administration/Computer Maintenance

United States Air Force - 1982 to 1986

Base Administration - Launched implementation procedures to automate a large inventory of AF publications and forms. Installed and configured all system hardware and software. Performed daily maintenance, and system backups. Received the Air Force Commendation Medal for my accomplishments on this project.

EDUCATION

4 Year Technical Degree in Microcomputers and Microprocessors

McGraw Hill National Radio Institute of Technology - Tampa, FL 1984 to 1987

Two Years in Computer Sciences

St. Leo College - Tampa, FL 1983 to 1984

SKILLS

See below under Additional Information (10+ years)

MILITARY SERVICE

Service Country: US Branch: Air Force

Rank: E3

August 1982 to August 1986

Commendations:

Air Force Commendation Medal

AWARDS

United States Air Force Commendation Medal

1986

CERTIFICATIONS/LICENSES

Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer (MCSE)

2008

Cisco CCNA

2004

CompTIA Network +

2000

CompTIA A+

1995

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Professional Skills

- Successful track record with increased responsibility in network engineering and analysis.
- Demonstrated capacity to implement and support enterprise-wide networking solutions.
- Possess adept leadership abilities; able to manage, motivate, and lead project teams using excellent communication and people skills.

Core Competencies

Hardware/Operating System Analysis; Network Engineering and Analysis; Network and Systems Security

Operating System Platforms: Microsoft DOS, Windows 95, 98, XP, NT, Windows 2000 Professional, Windows Vista, Windows 7, 2000 Server, 2003 Server, Novell Netware, Cisco IOS, Adtran IOS, and Linux.

Networking: Ethernet, VLAN, TCP/IP, VPN, SSH, FTP, DHCP, DNS, SNMP, DWDM, Microsoft Active Directory. Layer 2 and Layer 3 Devices from Cisco, HP, Alcatel, Allied Telesyn, MRV, and Netscreen/Juniper.

Tools: Cisco ASA, nGenius Infinistream, WhatsUpGold, HP iMC Platform, Websense, Bluecat DHCP/DNS, HP ATA, Sophos, MS Visio, HP TippingPoint, Network Associates Sniffer, LANGuard, Solarwinds Network Engineers Edition, SNMPc Management Console, Watchguard Firewall, Sourcefire IDS, IPrism, Barracuda Networks, Solarwinds, Websense.